

# Contact

# **Phone**

+27(0)84 596 7038

# **Email**

vanvuurenjohann124@gmail.com

# Location

Johannesburg, South Africa

# **Expertise / Stack**

- HTML5
- CSS3
- SCSS | LESS
- JavaScript (Vanilla)
- VCS: Git I GitHub
- React.js
- Bootstrap | React Bootstrap
- Node.js
- Express.js
- MongoDB | Mongoose
- JWT Authentication
- Java
- JDBC
- SQL (MySQL | MySQLi)
- Relational Database Design
- PHP
- WordPress

# **JOHANN JANSEN VAN VUUREN**

# WEB APPLICATION AND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# **About Me**

My career started as a BSc student, majoring in chemistry and biochemistry at the University of the Witwatersrand. It was also there that I had my first scientific position as laboratory assistant in the organic chemistry department. Before finishing my studies I was offered a position in the leading Pathology Laboratory in South Africa and spent the next 22 years working in clinical pathology.

Computer programming has been a hobby of mine throughout the years, starting at University and I soon realised that my heart yearns to work in the web and software development industry. I finally decided to take the plunge and resigned from my pathology career to pursue my dreams full time.

I am currently enrolled in HyperionDev's Immersive Full-Stack and Software Engineer Bootcamp. Due to my 100% average score in the BootCamp and volunteer work as a student champion I was offered a position of coding mentor even though my boot camp is still in progress. Together with this formal skills development and my plethora of skills picked up over the years in the clinical pathology environment I believe that I would be an asset to any organisation. My employment interest is particularly in remote or even freelance working positions.

# **Experience**

# HyperionDev -July 2022 - current

Coding Mentor August 2022 - current Student Champion (Volunteer)

# Ampath National Laboratories November 2006 - November 2020

Pathology Liaison / Hospital Marketer 2006 - 2016 Area Marketer and IT Superuser 2016 - 2020

## Ampath National Laboratories March 1998 - July 2006

Coordinating Technologist 1998 - 2000 Laboratory Night Manager 2000 - 2003 Client Services Manager 2003 - 2006

# East Rand Medicine Supplies 1993 - March 1998

Pharmacist's Assistant (Casual Position)

# **Education**

#### 1992

HoërSkoel Alberton

# Senior Certificate (Matric)

1993 - 1995

Wits University

BSc (Not completed)

#### 2007

Wits University

# Certificate in Warfarin Anticoagulation Management

# 2022 - 2023

HyperionDev

Immersive Full Stack & Software Engineering Boot Camp (90% Completed)

# JOHANN JANSEN VAN VUUREN

# WEB APPLICATION AND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# **RESPONSIBILITIES IN PREVIOUS POSITIONS**

#### HyperionDev -July 2022 - current

# **Coding Mentor August 2022 - Current**

Review students' work and use of the review platform to assist students in their continuous improvement as developing

Tutoring and assisting onsite students with troubleshooting and debugging their code.

Assisting students on the online chat forums with difficulties and requests for individual support or extra information. Upskilling on the Immersive Full Stack and Software Engineering Boot Camp that I am currently enrolled in. This boot camp involved several capstone projects modelling real-world coding projects across the spectrum of skills listed under the stack

## **Student Champion (Volunteer)**

Assisting fellow students in the online forums with coding difficulties or clarification of any theory.

#### Ampath National Laboratories November 1998 - November 2020

#### **Abilities**

- > Management of pre-analytical and client services environments in a pathology laboratory.
- > Handling of client inquiries with respect to test results and test requirements or availability.
- > Extensive technical knowledge of tests, specimen requirements, test interferences and other laboratory requirements.
- > Handling of any complaints irrespective of the area or discipline as well as effective resolution of complaints with exceptional client service in mind.

  > Extensive knowledge of test availability in South Africa as well as the indications of these tests.

- Excellent computer skills as well as extensive knowledge of the Meditech and QlikView Business Analytics Systems.
   Compilation of management, business intelligence and business statistical metrics reports for review by senior

#### **Duties while employed by Ampath:**

- Marketing and client satisfaction / liaison at several hospitals in Sandton and the East Rand.
  One-on-one interaction with high profile clients and personal management of all aspects of the service rendered to them. This includes review of results to minimise errors and ensure excellent turnaround time, handling of any result inquiries as well as any special needs that these clients may require on a day to day basis.
- Troubleshooting with regards to unsatisfactory service and laboratory / nursing errors.
- Consultation with specialist physicians with regards to appropriate laboratory investigations and rare tests. This included the marketing of new tests and client education in their use.

- Meditech troubleshooting with regards to site rules, data capturing and various forms of audit trails.
  Very good understanding of the various Meditech dictionaries.
  Interaction with clients with regards to the electronic results capabilities of Ampath (I.e., web solutions, smart device applications, mobile results and email schedules) and finding tailor made solutions for each client.
- Hosting of academic ward rounds with presenters from Wits University as well as CPD journal clubs.
- Preparation of quotations and set-up of industrial / corporate clients.
- Preparation of a monthly presentation of client and requisition statistics for business intelligence purposes using the
- Preparation of a monthly business unit report to the area managing pathologist and QC manager.
- Certification in Warfarin anticoagulation management by the University of the Witwatersrand (School of Pathology).
   Responsible for patient education, counselling and dosing of laboratory controlled Warfarin patients under the guidance of a haematopathologist.

LINKEDIN PROFILE: https://www.linkedin.com/in/johann-jansen-van-vuuren-33553273/ GITHUB PROFILE: https://github.com/JohannJvanVuuren